Context is extremely important.
Developers reports that 33 to 80%
depends on which tech and how you ask
it. And that's your number one request
from coding agent to improve. Like when
you think about context on one hand it
is like you have too much not accurate.
The other is like exactly only what you
need. In the middle could be like a lot
of nonrelevant but all the relevant etc.
But one of the hardest thing is actually
bringing the right context and then
making sure it's only that there. These
are the priorities and then that could
define a lot. There are certain tasks
that are super repeatable, super
automatable where you can get [music]
just another level of automation,
another level of productivity boost by,
you know, running multiple agents in the
cloud. What we've tried to build with
the open hands SDK is like a single
framework that allows you to create
multiple multiple different agents and
then getting those agents talking to
each other. It gives you kind of like a
single framework for thinking about how
to coordinate multiple agents together.
[music]
Before we jump into this episode, I
wanted to let you know that this podcast
is for developers building with AI at
the core. So whether that's exploring
the latest tools, the workflows, or the
best practices, this podcast's for you.
A really quick ask, 90% of people who
are listening to this haven't yet
subscribed. So if this content has
helped you build smarter, hit that
subscribe button and maybe a like. All
right, back to the episode.
Hey, I'm here still at QCON and uh get
look who I bumped into in the corridor.
It's Freriedman, CEO of Kodo. Um it's
how are you?
>> Great to bump into you.
>> Absolutely.
>> Such a great conference. So it's like
having fun here.
>> And of course, you've been on Aative Dev
twice, I think. So twice. Yeah. Yeah.
But first time on the podcast.
>> Yeah.
>> First time on the podcast. What was your
session about today? I think you've
already you've just given it.
>> Yeah, I just uh came back from it there.
So, multi- aent system uh I gave a
motivation behind why you want to have
that to start with like specifically for
software development uh uh talking about
like code quality, bad code, good code
um software development life cycle in
general and how we want to cover it. And
that was the first half of the
motivation. And then like we dived into
different architectural decisions that
you need to make when you're
implementing multi- aent systems uh when
you're developing a multi- aent system
for your software development life
cycle. Interesting. Uh actually there
was a paper by Google just recently. So
I even managed to squeeze that. It's 5
days old.
>> Yeah. Oh really? Wow. That's nice. Good
timing. Yeah.
>> So when talking about multiple or multi-
aent systems, are you talking about
multiple agents that can then therefore
like um code in parallel or are you
talking about different agents that do
different roles, different jobs, look
after each other where one codes, the
other one code reviews, that kind of
thing.
>> Exactly that. I mean like uh you can
have multi- you can have multi-coding
agents both like all of them writing
code in parallel or sequential and you
need to decide how you want to do that.
you can have a diversity of uh agents
with different roles and why we talked
about why you need them at all. Uh and
then like how do you see like do they
run in parallel or after like the coding
agents or or before.
>> So so roughly speaking there's multiple
consideration you need to have. Uh for
example, let me give you like a concrete
example. Let's say that you have an
agent that helps you with the planning
>> and then you have an agent that helps
you with the coding and then they don't
agree with each other. How do you decide
like what's how do you have a third
agent which is arbiter that makes a
decision etc and like there's different
consideration that you need to have.
>> Is there value in saying like I'm going
to use different models different
different agents uh different vendors of
agents in terms of doing different
roles. I guess it's almost like having
diversity in a team right where you have
different people thinking differently
and and and almost like contradicting
each other where they where you almost
like say actually this is how I think
this should be done. if you have all
agents that are the same agents but
>> you know still having those different
roles.
>> Yeah.
>> What what's the contrast between those
two scenarios?
>> So I think some people when they're
thinking about different agents the
first like thing pops into mind some
people is like okay I give it a
different prompt or something like that
>> that that architecture is basically like
an architecture of uh one single agent
that rules them all that all you need to
do is give it different tools and uh and
and and different like prompt or or so.
Uh that's one option. Uh the other
option is that agents are much more
different than that. For example, their
entire architecture, their graph of how
they build might be completely
different. For example, if you're doing
if you're dealing with a coding agent,
then in order to really do its job like
it's actually at least until now proven
that you need to enable it creativity.
Yeah. Because we developers, we bump
into a lot of issues and we bypass in
this and that like and actually the fact
that core is an LLM making the decision
is a good architecture for a coding
agent at least what we're seeing for
example in Swedbenge if you're familiar
>> and then when you're talking about other
types of agent for example you want to
have a security agent or you want to
have a code review agent that agent
might want to have actually much more
structure checking A B C D for example
you might have like 100 rules that's how
do you get them with subtopic we can
talk about we want to have 100 rules
that you want to make sure that are
obeyed and then you want that agent
review agent to be much more struct like
structured there is an LLM there but the
graph of that agent might be like uh 1
to 10 there where LLM is involved but
actually it's quite quite structured
there so and and by the way you might
give it different permissions etc so so
overall like there's a discussion do you
have one agent that rules it all or
multiple uh multiple agents what we're
seeing of course like when you're
jiggling dealing with enterprisegrade
heavyduty brown field when compliance
standardization etc. You must have like
different agents that are completely
different than each other, have
different context, have different
>> and do you find do you find different
vendors? So maybe like I don't know a
claude code or sorry Claude or something
like that. Do you find like that will be
better in a specific role? So like is
there is there a specific vendor that is
best for code reviews or or security
testing like you said? Yeah, actually
it's a good like uh point to to continue
from my last point where
>> different vendors have different DNA and
different like point of view on the
world like on on entropic believe at
least what I understand is that models
everything
>> and you need to give that model the
brain of everything and you need to give
them like agents in order to operate in
the world these tools needs to be quite
simple actually on the fly why do you
need to start doing retrieval augmented
generation just give it a simple tool
like ASD grap etc that's actually pretty
good like uh I I believe uh uh let's say
structure and and way of thinking for
coding agents. Yeah. But then when you
look under review security review agent
if you're familiar like three four five
months ago what all the rage and you
took a look on the prompt
>> you are now a security review agent and
then there is a prompt and then there is
like a list of exclusion don't look at
DOS don't look on that
>> like basically it's when you're doing a
security agent you need one plus of one
minus of that
>> you here is everything that you need to
check rigorously and then you can be
creative on all the rest
>> when you're encoder encoding agent you
want to relax this and say what what
not. But when you're doing a re security
agent then actually you need to do a one
minus of what they're doing. Yeah.
>> So I would use their their uh cloud code
for example as a vendor when you're
talking about cloud code as code coding
agent. Uh but I don't think it's like
you can just set up with a different
prompt to to to be like all all type of
agents out there. You need a different
vendor.
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. Uh and very
briefly because I see people people are
kicking out now so it might get a bit
noisy but very very briefly in terms of
context like security is a great example
where there are there's a ton of context
that you can provide an agent say look
here are your rules this is what you
have to check for at what point does at
what point where uh does the task that
you give an agent just becomes so
overwhelming it starts doing a poor job
security review is a great example code
review maybe even with you know a large
number of styling rules and those types
of things where's the limit for that
>> yeah context is extremely important you
know I can superlative context is the
king the kingdom uh etc. But it's
extremely important actually I talked
about it that uh developers reports that
33 to 80 80% depends on which uh tech
and and how you ask it think that
context is actually the major problem of
of bad quality and hallucination and
thing like that and that's your number
one request from coding agent to to
improve the thing is that context is not
just one thing it's not just a code base
it could be for example a database of
vulnerabilities it could be for example
kodto is the leading code review tool
for example we have database related to
best practices and rules that we project
depending on the stack of that what you
have etc. And we learn it from different
like interaction with developers in the
context engine. We collect a database
that related to best practices and rules
and then like it's really like you
really need to fetch the right the right
context and and then it's it's not just
like when you think about context on one
hand it is like
>> you have too much not accurate
>> the like the other is like exactly only
what you need in the middle for example
it could be like uh a lot of uh
nonrelevant but all the relevant etc.
Yeah.
>> So, so it's kind of a spectrum and of
course uh like the one of the hardest
thing is actually bringing the right
context and and then what we see the
hardest bringing the right context and
then making sure it's only that there
these are these are the priorities and
then that could define a lot for example
as I mentioned security companies might
have context relevant for security that
regular coding agent do not have code
review uh solution like codto might have
additional context that is relevant to
best practice standard etc that regular
coding agent don't have that's how the
way I look at it. How do you bring the
right context and then cut that you
don't have too much because there is
like the the context rot if you want to
read more about it that's like entropic
and other company talk about the context
rot. Yeah, super super interesting and
but yeah, so correct as so so right as
well because context giving too much
context you think okay I've got all
these rules that I need to follow you
throw it all in one go and actually it's
just going to forget what it wants to
forget or it's not going to add it it's
not going to
>> I think if I connect all the dots we
talked about context is very important
maybe one of the most important and then
is how you use them when you upload for
example context cloud code or cursor for
them it's like part of the you know part
of their like just literally the context
and then they just keep pushing that in
the context in their graph. If you like
give it same prompt with the same
context seven times you get seven
different solutions.
>> But but uh so like I do want to say like
context is important but then how you
use it while maybe other tools will use
it very differently more like in a
workflow verifying different things etc.
So context is extremely important uh and
the I just want to add on what you're
saying not completely following the
context is also a matter of how you
build the agent. Yeah, absolutely.
>> So that's another point.
>> It's been awesome. It's been awesome
catching up.
>> Hello. Joining me here is Robert Brennan
who is the CEO of Open Hands. Robert,
good to see you here.
>> Yeah, good to see you as well.
>> And of course, I saw you here, well, not
here, but in New York only a few weeks
ago for AI Native DevCon.
>> Yeah, good to see you again.
>> Yeah, no, likewise.
>> What's your session going to be about
today?
>> So, we're going to be talking about how
to scale code maintenance with AI
agents. Um, I would say there's a lot of
tasks where developers are uh for like
their day-to-day feature development.
They're used to like pairing with cloud
code or the openhand CLI locally on
their laptop. Uh, that works great for
your like ad hoc work. You know, you
pick up a ticket, you need to work on
it. Uh, but there are certain tasks that
are super repeatable, super automatable
where you can get just another level of
uh automation, another level of
productivity boost by, you know, running
multiple agents in the cloud to take
down these like very automatable tech
oriented uh tasks. Awesome. And and I
guess you know when we talk about
maintenance, what what kind of things
are we talking about? Typical
maintenance tasks that a developer would
do?
>> Yeah. So very typical things would be
things like um like dependency
management uh you know resolving open
source vulnerabilities that happen in
your codebase. Um and then some meteor
tasks like you know maybe upgrading from
Python 2 to Python 3 or upgrading you
know from an old version of Java to a
new version of Java, maybe migrating
from Cobalt to Java or another more
modern programming language. Uh there's
a lot of these like toiley tasks that
developers don't really like doing. They
don't involve a lot of creativity or
critical thinking. Uh it's mostly just a
lot of like churning out lines of code.
Um but they're still too big for uh you
know a single agent to oneshot in many
cases. U and so uh doing what we call
agent orchestration uh can allow you to
you know put some forethought into how
you're going to solve this repeatable
problem in a way that can scale across
many code bases uh and then just uh you
know automate it 90% of the way there uh
and just have a human in the loop for
you know the very little bit where you
need that last uh last bit of
verification.
>> So let's talk about agent orchestration
then. So when we talk about agent
orchestration we're obviously talking
about multiple agents. Do they have to
be the same agent or can they just be
different vendors that that kind of
thing? Yeah, I think it's it's helpful
to be working within like a single agent
framework, right? Uh there's nothing
necessarily stopping, you know, one
agent from talking to another agent. Um
and there are, you know, there's the ADA
protocol and things like that. Um but
what we've tried to build with the open
hands SDK is like a single framework
that allows you to create multiple
multiple different agents with like
different system prompts, different sets
of tools that they have access to, uh
different MCP servers that they have
access to, um and you know, maybe
different um behavior patterns, right?
Um and then getting those agents talking
to each other is uh you know it gives
you kind of like a single framework for
thinking about how to uh you know
coordinate multiple agents together
>> right and when we think about when we
start with kind of like a large task
typically that a number of agents can
can all work on um we don't obviously
just throw that large task at all these
agents group of agents we need to break
that task down what's the process of
kind of breaking that down is there is
there amount of human interaction in
that or can we uh somewhat automate that
for AI as well
>> yeah I think that's that's kind of the
the most critical step is like how are
you going to break this problem down
into subpieces that individual agents
can execute on right
>> um so I think that's where the most
human thought goes into the process but
you can you know work with uh you know
an LLM like Claude for instance to kind
of talk through the problem and help
like get get some help from uh an LLM to
break down the problem into manageable
bite-sized tasks but you're also going
to have to really lean on your own
intuition for what is actually solvable
uh what's reviewable by a human you know
what what can you give to the agent that
you can and look at on the other end
when it when it gives you some output
and quickly verify did it do the thing
or did it not.
>> Mhm. How important is parallelization in
this? Because I guess when we think
about like breaking down that task, not
all of it can kind of run all at the
same time. So we need we need some level
of dependency where one thing relies
upon or depends on the output of the
other. How's that graph almost worked
out?
>> Yeah, I think the more you can paralyze
the better, especially for these very
big tasks. Uh like a really good example
is we have one client that's literally
fielding thousands of new CVE
announcements per day across their very
massive codebase. Um and what they do is
they send out agents in parallel to go
solve those CVEs across the entire
codebase.
>> Um and uh you know if they were trying
to do that iteratively it would just it
would just take forever right but uh
being able to parallelize this A means
they go a lot faster and b means that if
like one of these you know one of these
CVs fails to resolve maybe there's just
like no way to resolve it. um you know
we don't get stuck right you you have uh
you know you know 90% might get solved
and then you can focus on that 10% that
like didn't didn't quite make it through
>> u but yeah very very tricky to figure
out how to decompose a task so that you
can get the most amount out of
parallelization
>> I guess like there's an amount of human
to agent interaction here as well what
stage does the human kind of like what
stage is there kind of like more chat or
more preparation does the human then
just kind of like leave it and then just
wait for the all the results to come in
how much interaction is there?
>> Uh I think it's very very task
dependent, right? Um and that's that's
you know when we talk about agent
orchestration and like the skill that
goes into agent orchestration. uh a big
uh consideration you need to you need to
uh take into account as you you know use
agents to solve a particular problem is
where am I going to stick the human in
the loop so that I can understand that
these are working well uh that the
agents aren't just like going you know
spending hours and you know hundreds of
dollars or even more uh you know going
down a wrong path right you want to make
sure that there are regular check-ins to
make sure that you know the agents are
on the right track um and that you know
you're not shipping anything into
production that a human hasn't like
properly reviewed and QA tested and
things like that
>> and there trust issue there as well like
in terms of when we are thinking about
okay let's update some you know
potential new CVS and some dependencies
or or whatever it is there's an amount
of production code that's being touched
and this this the there's always a
danger my my background in sneak
whenever there was a kind of like change
there's there's an amount of there's an
amount of effort in that change that is
required that could potentially cause an
issue in production um how how like in
your experience do you see people
onboarding to this type of mentality of
I'm just going to allow these agents to
kind of go and do their thing.
>> What What is there a buildup or or
growth of trust that needs to occur?
>> Yeah, I would definitely encourage folks
to start small.
>> Um, you know, dependency updates are a
great one that you know, we're actually
pretty used to that being automated with
things like dependabot.
>> Um, uh, AI agents allow you to get like
another level of uh, automation there
for when there are like breaking API
changes and things like that. There
might be a few lines of code that need
to change. Mhm.
>> Um yeah, starting starting with smaller
tasks that are easier for the human to
verify uh easier to QA uh is definitely
uh the way to kind of like get your feet
wet with this sort of thing and then as
you build trust and as you build
intuition for what uh agents do well and
what they don't do well then you can
like increase the scale of your efforts
here um as you as you start to build
that trust. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Awesome. So if a developer
wanted to get started with this and and
and get going and use open hands to do
that, what would the what would the way
you would recommend they I guess where
should they go to get started? But what
would what would the first steps be to
to build this in?
>> Yeah. So I mean the first thing would be
to identify some repeatable problem that
happens in your organization, right? So
very common one would be like we have a
bunch of repos that are using Java
version 8 which is you know way out of
support. We want to get everybody to
Java version 21. Um you know maybe we've
got a hundred repos that have this
problem. Um, uh, I would start by
picking one of those repos and using
like the openhand CLI or our web UI to
just iterate through the problem
yourself, like try to prompt your way to
success and see what that takes. Um, and
you'll get you'll get more intuition for
the problem and more intuition for like
how agents uh, are able to help you
solve this problem. So yeah, I think
once you've once you've built up that
intuition for the problem by doing it
kind of manually and prompting your way
to it, uh then you can uh use you know
an SDK like the open hands SDK to
actually encode that you know as Python
uh or some other programming language.
Um you can you can put that intuition
kind of into enforcement uh and build an
orchestrated pipeline for achieving that
across many different repository
something that can be repeated
>> and that's a really nice parallelization
route as well. It's the same thing but
just across many many reps. I love the
idea of learning that by yourself the
more manual way and then trying to scale
that out because you learn I guess as a
developer you'll know ah there's a
little gotcha here that I wasn't
thinking about that if I had scaled that
straight away it would have been a
problem.
>> Exactly.
>> Um and one final one final question um
what are the kind of the the nicest
scenarios for a developer to start with
this kind of thing obviously you know
they can probably kick it off through
the APIs themselves. Yeah.
>> Are there ways in which we can integrate
this through triggers maybe PR requests
that have been opened all those types of
things as well?
>> Totally. Yeah. Yeah. So, OpenHands
integrates basically anywhere developers
live, right? Slack, GitHub, Jira, uh,
GitLab, Bitbucket. U, basically anywhere
there's information that you might want
to pull into an agent. Uh, you can just
say at openhands do the thing. Um, and
then I would say for more advanced use
cases, we also have like an API where
um, you know, you can build some
automation so that say anytime a certain
event happens in data dog, uh, you can
then use that to kick off an openhand
session via the API uh, and fix the
underlying error. So, even if that error
happens at like 2:00 in the morning, you
wake up to a poll request that fixes it
the next day.
>> Amazing. Well, Robert, you've got a
session to go to in about 40 minutes, so
looking forward to hearing more about
that. But, uh, pleasure to see you here
again. Thanks for having me. Cheers.